Student:Hi,Positive Psychs.We are Fallen Angels.
幸福课的同学们你们好 我们是Fallen Angels
This Saturday,March 15,is our debut in Centers.
这周六 3月15号 是我们在中心剧场的首次公演
We are gonna be singing with Harvard Opportunes.
我们将和哈佛Opportunes乐团共同出演
So We'd love to see all your positive faces there.
希望能在那时见到你们快乐的脸庞
It's Saturday,8 pm.
周六晚八点
You can get your tickets at the Harvard Box Office,
可以在哈佛票务中心买票
from any Opportune,or from your favorite Angel.
也可以找Opportunes团员 或者来找你最爱的天使
(singing PINK "Who Knew")
演唱"谁知道"
If someone said three years from now
如果有人曾说三年以后
You'd be long gone
你早已离去
I'd stand up and punch them out
我会站起来将他们推出去
They'd be all wrong
因为他们都是错的
I know better
我知道不是这样
Cause you said forever
因为你说过会陪我
And ever,who knew?
直到永远 谁知道呢
My darling,I miss you
亲爱的 我想你
My darling,who knew
亲爱的 谁知道
Student:I have tickets.So find me after class.
我手上有票 下课可以来找我
They are 8 dollars.Find me.
每张八美元 来找我吧
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Carpe Diem.Seize the day.
抓住眼前 及时行乐
So let's continue on this path and go a little bit more in depth
让我们沿着这个理念再深入一点
into this idea of self-concordance.
探讨一下自我和谐
What are some benefits of self-concordance?
自我和谐有什么好处呢
The first one-
自我和谐
and there are many- the first one is the obvious one.
有很多好处 其中第一点非常显而易见
You don't need to be a rocket scientist
你不需要成为一个火箭科学家
or even a social scientist to understand that
或者社会科学家 就能理解
setting self-concordant goals can potentially make us happier.
制定自我和谐的目标可以让我们更快乐
Because we are pursuing something we care about,
因为我们在追求自己在意的事
it is more likely to reinforce our enjoyment of the journey.
更加增加了人生旅途的乐趣
The second thing,in addition to increasing well being,
第二 除了增加幸福感
certainly connected to well being is that very often,
当然也跟幸福感紧密相关的是
having self-concordant goals- having goals in general,
制定自我和谐的目标 整体上制定目标
but in particular self-concordant goals,
但特别制定一些自我和谐的目标
resolves internal conflicts.
能解决内在的心理冲突
For example- it helps us deal with anxiety,
比如说 它可以帮我们解决焦虑
with uncertainty,with existential questions-
解决疑惑 解决有关存在的问题
"What am I about? What am I doing? Why am I here?"
"我是谁 我在干什么 我为什么在这儿"
And if you think about it,very often when we go through periods
如果你思考这些 通常是在那种
when we are not sure where we are going,
我们不确定该走向何方
where every fork in the road is about ambivalence and uncertainty
站在十字路口 前路迷雾重重的时候
that's when existential questions come up.
这就是有关存在的问题出现的时候
That's when there's uncertainty.
这就是犹豫出现的时候
That's when very often,there's unhappiness,
这就是不快乐出现的时候
whereas when we know what our path is,
如果我们知道我们该往哪儿走
it helps to resolve internal conflict.
就不会有那么多的内在心理冲突
An interesting way to think about it
我们可以从一个很有趣的角度来看它
is by drawing comparison to interpersonal conflicts.
也就是将它与人际间的冲突相对比
So here we are talking about intra-personal conflicts- within:
我们现在讲的是人的内在冲突 是心理内在的
anxiety,depression- often a result of that.
焦虑 沮丧 通常会造成类似的后果
But there's a lot of research on interpersonal conflicts.
有很多关于人际间冲突的研究
And I talked about briefly
我在讲到实践唯心主义
when I discussed practical idealism and conflict resolution.
以及冲突的解决时简单讲过
And the way to deal with the conflicts,
面对冲突的办法
the best way to deal with the conflicts and resolve them
面对并解决冲突的最好办法
is to have a super ordinate goal,
就是制定一个协调的目标
a goal in which both sides- both conflicting sides engage in
使得冲突的双方都参与其中
and are dependent on one another or intra-dependent.
并内在地相互依赖
And that resolves interpersonal or intergroup conflicts.
这样就能够解决人际间或组织间的冲突
This is work of Muzafer Sherif or Elliot Aronson.
这是Muzafer Sherif或Elliot Aronson所做的研究
In the same way,having a goal helps to solve internal conflicts,
同理 制定目标有助于解决内在冲突
intra-personal conflicts.
人内在的心理冲突
Because it takes our mind away from those existential,
因为它能让我们暂时忘却那些关于存在的
often important,but sometimes difficult questions,
很重要 但通常很难的问题
especially when they persist.
尤其是不断出现时
Away from anxiety.Away from depression.
它能使我们远离焦虑 远离沮丧
And we are focused on something we really,really want to do.
我们能集中精力于我们十分想做的事
Also,it increases the likelihood of success.
同时 它还增加了成功的可能性
Individuals who set self-concordant goals are more motivated-
制定了自我和谐目标的人会更有动力
they are more likely to work hard.
他们会更努力地工作
They are more likely to put their all in-
他们会全身心地投入到
whatever it is- that they are doing.
他们所做的事中去
In the long term,
从长远来看
those who pursue their passions are more likely to succeed.
那些追求自己热爱事业的人都更容易取得成功
Again,seems pretty straight forward,
这似乎非常直白
pretty self-evident common sense.
显而易见 简直是常识
But as we often said,common sense is not that common.
但我们常说 常识也并不是那么显而易见的
In many ways,
很大程度上说
this increased likelihood of success when we pursue the things
这种在我们追求自己热爱的事业时
that we are passionate about defines the "no pain,no gain" maxim
成功的可能性的增加 重新定义了"不劳无获"的公理
It defines it and changes it to the following maxim:
它将其重新定义为如下定理
"Do it better with pleasure."
"愉悦劳作则多获"
Now if you quote me on this,I'll deny it.
如果你要引用 我会否认我说过
If you show someone the video of me saying it,
如果你给别人看我说这句话的录像
I'll say that it's my cheesy twin brother who coined it.
我会说这是我的双胞胎兄弟
But it's true.
但确实是这样
We do do it better with pleasure if we pursue our passions.
如果我们热爱这项事业 就确实能把它做得更好
What happens in practice- again,there's a lot of research on it.
在实际生活中 同样也有很多关于这个的研究
You are reading some of it; I elaborate on some of it in the book
你们读到了一些 我把某些研究编进了书里
There's a lot of research that shows that
有很多研究显示
when we are engaged in a self-concordant goal,
当我们沉浸于自我和谐的目标时
we are much more likely
就会更倾向于
to then continue to pursue self-concordant goals.
继续追求其他自我和谐的目标
Because it was good that we were more successful;
因为这样很好 我们更成功了
we want more of it.It's self-reinforcing.
我们还不满足 这叫做自我强化
Not just on the macro level of life goals where it does that,
不仅是从生活目标的宏观角度来讲是这样
but also on the micro level.And what we see is a trickle effect.
微观角度也是这样 这其实是种涓滴效应
People who set self-concordant goals were actually doing better
制定了自我和谐目标的人其实
in areas that were not necessarily self-concordant.
在非自我和谐的方面也做得更好了
For instance-
打个比方
let's say you are a member of an undergrad A ccapella group.
比如说你是一个大学生合唱团的成员
And you really enjoy it.
你很喜欢这件事
In self-concordant,it's something that you believe in.
从自我和谐的角度来看 这是你所信仰的事
Something you enjoy.Something that is interesting to you.
是你喜欢的事 是你感兴趣的事
Something you are doing
是一件你正在做
because you are really want to be doing it.
因为你确实非常想做的事
In other words,a self-concordant goal that will have an effect,
换句话说 自我和谐的目标会对你生活的
a positive effect on other areas in your life-
其他方面产生积极影响
such as a class that you don't necessarily enjoy that much,
比如说一门你不那么喜欢的课
but you are doing more because you feel that you have to,
你去上课是因为你觉得你必须要去
as opposed to you really really want to.
而不是你真的非常想去
So potentially identifying self-concordant goals
因此找到自我和谐的目标
can also help you improve your grades.
其实可以帮助你提高成绩
Again,even though they are not related at all.
虽然它们似乎毫不相关
Because overall,you are more motivated; you are more excited;
因为总体来说 你更有动力了 你更兴奋了
you are more interested; and you enjoy life
你更感兴趣了 你用更积极的感情
as a whole more in positive emotions have a trickle effect.
来享受整个人生 这就是涓滴效应
In a way you can think about it like a candle in a dark room.
这个效应可以想象为黑暗房间里的蜡烛
Very often you don't need to light up the entire room with lights
通常你不需要将点很多灯照亮整个屋子
A single candle sometimes
有时只需一根蜡烛
is enough to spread the light to darkened corners of the room.
就足以将光明遍布房间每一个角落
The same with the self-concordant goals.
自我和谐的目标也是这样
They have a trickle effect.Choosing to do things-
它们具有涓滴效应
doing what we want to do has also health benefits.
选择做我们想做的事同样对健康也有好处
This is one of the most important studies done
这是心理学领域的重要研究之一
in the field of psychology by,once again,our own Ellen Langer.
同样是由我们学校的Ellen Langer做的研究
What she did was going into old age homes and divide it-
她所做的就是去了一个养老院
the old age home randomly into two groups.
将老人们随机分为两组
The one group got all the support that they needed-
第一组所有需要都能得到满足
whatever they wanted they got.
不管什么需要都能满足
They asked for certain food- they got it.
他们想吃什么 就能吃什么
They asked to be helped,carrying out certain tasks- they got it.
他们想在某些事情上寻求帮助 同样也能满足
Everything was done for them.
所有事情都无需他们动手
In many ways,the old age homes that many people dream of.
很大程度上来说 这是大多数人梦想的养老院
And then the second group didn't have as good.
而第二组就没有这么好的待遇了
Not everything was catered for them.
他们不能衣来伸手饭来张口
They very often had to do their own things.
时常都需要自己动手
For example,notably,they had to water their own plants.
比如说 他们必须自己浇花
They very often had to set their own routine during the day.
他们必须自己规划每天做的事
The service wasn't as great as the first group.
服务没有第一组那么周到
They had to tell the employees if they needed something.
他们需要什么的话 必须自己告诉职员
They very often had to get it themselves.
经常需要自己动手丰衣足食
And again,they planted- they watered their own plants.
同样 他们需要自己浇花
And what they did was-
而研究的内容是
Langer created this two different scenarios
Langer创造了这两种不同的情境
and then went back 18 months later.
然后一年半后再回来
After 18 months,the second group,
一年半后 第二组
the group that watered their plants,
自己浇花的那一组
the group that took care of their day,
自己照顾自己的那一组
the group that was not catered for,
没有人管顾的那一组
in the same way as the first group-
跟第一组相比起来
they were less likely to be depressed; they were happier;
他们没那么沮丧 他们更快乐
they were more energetic; more independent,physically healthier.
他们更有活力 更独立 也更健康
And the clincher:
更关键的是
18 months later,they were 50 percent more likely to be alive.
一年半后 他们活着的比例比另一组高出一半
The only difference being that group that was healthier,happier,
唯一的区别就在于更健康 更开心
more likely to be alive,had choice.
更高存活率的这组 有选择的权利
They did their own thing.
他们能做自己想做的事
They were asked what do you want to do,
他们会询问自己想做什么
as opposed to being catered for,being supported.
而不是衣来伸手饭来张口
And in some way,this was too easy.There was no choice involved.
从某种角度来说 这太轻松了 不需要做什么选择
And when we choose,when we do what we want to,
当我们能够选择时 当我们做自己想做的事时
it has implications to our well being,to our success,
是有益于我们的幸福 我们的成功
and to our physical health,
以及我们的健康的
to the point of leading to longer life.
尤其是能使我们更加长寿
Significant difference with such little intervention.
小小的差异导致了巨大的区别
And yet,so many of the old age homes today are built
但今天的很多养老院依然是基于
around the notion of "let's catered to all their needs"-
"迎合老人所有的需要"
"let's do everything that they desire",
"满足他们所有需求"
"let's make it easy for them".That's not necessarily good.
"为他们提供方便"这样的理念上的 这其实不好
There's too easy-
太过于轻松了
whether it's the notion that I talked about in the book,
不管是我在书里提到的概念
"the underprivilege of the privilege",
"特权中的非特权"
or things are too easy,or we don't fail enough;
一切过于轻松 我们失败得不够
whether it is in the old age home,or it becomes too easy,
抑或是老人院里 一切过于轻松
as opposed to making choices and struggling and making decisions.
不需要做选择 无需挣扎 无需做决定
And it applies as we will see later also,
而且同样适用于我们之后会讲到的
to the notion of stress- and how important that can be
压力的概念 以及它对于
in cultivating resilience and ultimately,happiness.
培养耐性以及最终获得幸福的重要性
Too easy is not necessarily good.Finally,
过于轻松不一定是件好事
we see this also in oppressive regimes versus democracies.
最后我们看到压迫政权和民主之间也是这样
One of the main reasons why people are happier under democracies-
人们之所以在民主制度下更幸福的重要原因之一
and remember,that is one of few external circumstances
记住 这是少数可以预测幸福的
that can predict happiness-
外部条件之一
one of the reasons is because under democracies,people have choice.
原因之一就在于 民主制度下人们有选择的权利
As opposed to under dictatorships,
而在独裁政治下
very often they are told "OK,you need to go into accounting.
通常人们会被告知"好 你去做会计
You need to go into engineering.
你去做工程
And you need to go into athletics." And so on.
你去做运动员" 诸如此类
And when you have a choice,that is a good predictor of happiness
如果你有选择 那就是快乐的预示
Let's shift gear a little bit.
让我们稍微换一下话题
I'm going to talk about something very much related
我要讲一些与自我和谐非常相关的东西
to self-concordance,but from a different angle.
但是是从不同的角度来讲的
I'm going to talk about values in action,or in short,the VIA.
我要讲讲行为价值观 缩写为VIA
Values in action,the VIA,is arguably the most ambitious,
行为价值观 VIA 可以说是积极心理学中
and certainly one of the most important projects
最有前景 也是
within positive psychology.
最重要的课题之一
It was initiated by Chris Peterson in the picture,
它最先是由图中的Chris Peterson
professor of University of Michigan and Martin Seligman.
密歇根大学教授 以及Martin Seligman共同提出的
And what they wanted to identify was positive psychology
他们想说明的是积极心理学
is alternative to the DSM- the DSM,
可以代替DSM DSM就是
the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorder,which
《精神疾病诊断与统计手册》
is essentially the classification of all known mental disorders.
其中包括已知所有心理疾病的分类
It's a very thick book,a very important document where it says-
这是本非常厚的书 非常重要的文件 上面讲了
for example,it lists certain criteria
比如说 它列出了特定的标准
and it says if a person has seven of the ten of these criteria
然后说如果一个人在某一段时间内符合
for x period of time,that person has major depression.
这十条标准中的七条 那他就有重性抑郁症
If the person has three of four criteria for y period of time,
如果某人在另一段时间内符合四条标准中的三条
that person has schizophrenia.
他就有精神分裂症
Or dysthymia.Or seasonal affective disorder.
或抑郁症 或季节性心理疾病
Or all of the psychopathologies that are known to us,
或者我们已知的定义并分类好的
that have been defined and classified.
精神疾病
A very important document.
非常重要的文件
Come along Seligman and Peterson right at the beginning
而Seligman和Peterson
when positive psychology came onto the scene and say,
在积极心理学问世之初就说
"let's create an alternative.Let's create an alternative
"让我们来造一个替代品 让我们替代掉
to the DSM that will identify instead of weaknesses,
DSM 不再鉴别弱点
instead of pathologies,instead of deficiencies,
疾病 或者缺陷
it will identify individual strengths and virtues."
相反来鉴别人的力量和长处"
And they identified 24 character strengths,
然后他们定义了24种人格力量
all enlisted,explained,described in this book.
全部囊括在此书中 并进行了解释和描述
Not only did they identified the character strengths,
他们不仅定义了这些人格力量
they also created mechanisms,ways,
还创造了机制 方法
means of measuring these character strengths.
来测量这些人格力量
For example,an online test- one you would be taking next week-
比方说一个网上测试 下周你们会做一个这样的测试
that can help you,as a first step,
可以作为帮你鉴别你的
identify your values in actions:
行为价值观的第一步
what are your character strengths; what are your virtues;
你的人格力量是什么 你的美德是什么
what are you good at; what are you passionate about.
你擅长什么 你热爱什么
The thing about character strengths-When they identified them,
关于人格力量 他们在鉴别它们时
they made sure that they identified universal characteristics.
确保了他们所鉴别的是普遍的人格特点
In other words,it wasn't chosen by you know,
换句话说 并不是特别挑选的例如
male,white academics living in America.
美国的白人学术男性
This was research done all over the world,
这是在全球范围进行的研究
cross-culturally to identify characters that are identical,
跨文化以鉴别那些共有的特征
whether it was in United States or Europe,Asia- China,Japan
不管在美国 欧洲 亚洲的中国 日本
as well as the Massai tribe in Kenya
甚至包括肯尼亚的马萨伊部落
and the Inuits in Northern Greenland.
以及北格陵兰岛的因纽特人
So this was an international research project,
这是个全球范围的研究课题
because what they thought-
因为他们想
if we can find things that are common to all cultures,
如果我们能找到所有文化都共有的东西
we will identify what is the part of human nature,
就能找到人类本性的东西
as opposed to human nurture.
而不是后天养成的
And they admit you know that this may change over time;
他们承认这是可以随时间变化的
we may become more sophisticated in measuring them.
在测量时我们可能会变得更老练
But as a start,the character strengths and virtues,
但作为开始 人格力量和美德
the values in action,manual and test,is an excellent start,
行为价值观 手册和测试 是一个好的开始
the one what you'll benefit from a great deal,
你会从中受益良多
as you will see shortly.
很快你们就会明白
The key aspect also of these characteristics
这些特点的关键方面在于
is that they have moral value.
它们具有道德价值
For example,the ability to run fast-
例如跑得快的能力
it's certainly some people have this strength,
很显然有些人有这种能力
you know having more fast twitch than slow twitch,
身体各部位动得更快
having stronger muscles,for instance.
肌肉更强劲
It certainly is a strength,but it's not a character strength.
这是种力量 但不是人格力量
Because it doesn't in and of itself have a moral component.
因为它其中不含有道德成分
You could use your strength and your speed toward moral ends,
你可以将力量用于道德相关的事情
but in and of itself,
但就其本身来说
it has not been valued as a moral characteristic.
它并不算是一种道德特点
Similarly,in order for something to be a strength,
同理 一样东西要成为力量
it has to be used toward moral end.
就必须是用于道德方面的
For instance- as you'll see,
比方说
humor is one of the character strengths.However,
幽默是一种人格力量
if humor is used to hurt other people as it sometimes is,
但如果幽默被用来伤害他人
it cannot be considered a strength.
它就不能算作一种力量
So it's used toward moral noble ends.
所以它必须是用于道德高尚的方面
What values in action are in many ways-
行为价值观很大程度上是
they are about self-concordant journey.Meaning:
关于自我和谐的过程的 意思是
when we set a goal and outcome,we are about a destination-
当我们制定了目标和结果 有一个目的地
yes,it certainly benefits the journey.
对 这当然是对整个过程有益的
Yes,it certainly helps us enjoy by liberating us-
它通过解放我们来帮助我们
helps us enjoy the here and now.
享受现在 享受当下
But ultimately,what our focus is on- the end result.
但最终我们关注的是结果
With values in action,
有了行为价值观
our focus is on specifically,directly the journey.
我们就能直接关注这个过程
How can I enjoy getting to the end,my destination?
我如何能到达终点 我的目的地
Is it by engaging in a lot of learning?
是通过大量的学习吗
Is it by- which may be a character strength of mine,
是通过我可能拥有的人格力量之一
love of learning? Is it by engaging leading other people-
对学习的热爱吗 还是通过领导他人呢
the leadership is one of those character strengths?
领导也是人格力量之一
Is it by being spiritual and praying along the path-
是通过精神上的祈祷吗
if spirituality or awe is my character strengths.
如果信仰和敬畏是我的人格力量的话
So it's helping us enjoy the journey
它们能帮助我们享受
on the way to a destination we deem valuable.
前往我们认为有价值的目的地的过程
In other words,
换句话说
if we have a self-concordant end and a self-concordant journey,
如果我们有自我和谐的目标和自我和谐的旅程
this is what happiness is.
这就是快乐的所在
Both present benefit (journey)
既包括当下的好处(过程)
as well as future benefit (outcome).
也包括将来的好处(结果)
And that's why it goes hand in hand with a self-concordant goal.
这就是为什么自我和谐的目标很重要
It's not that the self-concordant goals
并不是说自我和谐的目标
don't help us enjoy the journey,
对我们享受奋斗的过程没有帮助
and it's on the VIA does not help us reach a better outcome.
而VIA也不能帮我们得到更好的结果
It does.
它其实可以
However, when they go together, we are more likely to experience
然而 当它们同时呈现时 我们更能够感受到
a complete experience of happiness,of fulfillment.
完整的快乐 以及成就感
And a lot of research has shown how identify our values in action
很多研究显示如何找到我们的行为价值观
and more importantly applying them,using them,
更重要的是如何应用它们
exercising them leads to higher levels of happiness and success.
能够使我们得到更高层次的快乐和成功
And this is not just correlational;
这不仅仅是相关关系
there is a causal relationship.
而是因果关系
And your exercise for next week will be to implement it,
你们下周的练习就是使用它
which will ultimately hopefully lead you to more success
最终可能带你们走向更大的成功
as well as more of the ultimate currency.
以及终极的目标
In addition to the questionnaire that you will be taking,
除了你们即将做的问卷之外
here are some other criteria to identify
这里也有一些其他的标准来鉴别
what are your personal character strengths.
你的个人人格力量是什么
The first one is "is this the real me?"
第一个问题就是"这是真的我吗"
Do I feel authentic,most myself,when I am working in a group?
我是否觉得这真的是我自己 当我在团体里工作时
When I am leading people? When I am learning something new?
当我领导别人时 当我学新东西时
When I am praying? When I'm watching a comedy
当我祈祷时 当我在看一部喜剧
or telling jokes or listening to jokes?
或者讲笑话 听笑话时
When do I feel most myself?
我什么时候觉得最是我自己
William James,back in the 19th century:
十九世纪时 William James说
"I have often thought the best way to define a man's character
"我时常觉得定义一个人性格的最好办法
would be to seek out the particular mental
就是寻找特定的心理
or moral attitude in which,when it came upon him,
或道德态度 它们出现时
he felt himself most deeply and intensely active and alive.
他觉得自己最为积极和活跃
At such moments there is a voice inside which speaks and says:
在这种时刻 他内心有一个声音说
'This is the real me!'"
'这就是真的我!'"
When is the real you coming out? Is it when you act bravely?
你的真我在什么时候出现呢 是你表现英勇的时候吗
Is it when you apply yourself and work hard at something?
是你全身心投入 认真地做某事的时候吗
Is it when you plan- and you are prudent,
是你作为一个审慎的人 你的计划
careful about the future? It's a strength,too.
很好地计划了未来的时候吗 这也是一种力量
When you are acting according to your character strengths,
当你按照你的人格力量行为时
you feel energized and you feel motivated.
你会觉得充满活力和动力
It comes from within.It feels natural.
这是发自内心的 很本能的
Again,this is about understanding your personal nature,
这是来自你的人性本能的
the constrained view of human nature,
本质的内在观念
as opposed to saying "well,all the strengths are me.
而不是说"所有力量都是我的
I can cultivate all the strengths." Yes,it's true.
我可以培养所有这些力量" 对 没错
And we all have some of all of the strengths.
我们都拥有所有力量中的一些
However,however,we also have certain inclinations embedded
然而 我们仍然有特定的偏向 它植根于
whether it's in our genes,
我们的基因
whether it's in our earlier experiences.And
或者早期的经历
it's not we cannot or should not cultivate the other strength,
并不是说我们就不能或不应该培养其他力量
but what we need to do
而是我们应该
is focus mostly on those strengths that are most natural to us.
更专注于这些对我们来说更本性的力量
Because that's when we get the most bank for the buck,
因为这是我们能获取最多的地方
so to speak,in the ultimate currency that is,
也就是说最终的结果
as well as in success,the conventional standard of success.
最后的成功 传统意义上的成功
And when we engage in those strengths,our personal strengths,
当我们利用这些力量 个人的力量时
that's when we grow the most,that's when we develop the most,
我们最能够成长 最能发展
that's when we learn the most.
学到的也最多
And again,ask yourself as in a minute
再问问自己 很快你们就会
you'll be looking at the list of strengths- ask yourself:
看到列出各种力量的单子 问问自己
when does it feel the real me?
我什么时候最能感觉到自我
Again,it's when I apply myself and work hard?
是我投入地工作时吗
Is it when I go again the grain and act bravely?
是我惩恶扬善表现英勇时吗
Is it when I feel the most real,the most alive?
这是我觉得最真实 最有活着的感觉的时候吗
Is it when I learn something new? Is it when I go to a museum?
是我学习新知识时吗 是我去博物馆时吗
Is it when I pray? Is it when I'm around people who are funny?
是我祈祷时吗 是我被幽默的人环绕时吗
When is it the most me? Here is the list.
什么时候我最真实? 这是力量的列表
Take just a minute to look at them.
花一分钟看看
They are divided into six categories.
它们分为六个类别
There are 24 character strengths.
共有24种人格力量
And I just want you to be exposed to it right now.
我只是让你们提前看看
Because,again,for your homework,
因为你们的作业中
you'll get a print-out of all the strengths with description.
会拿到一份带描述的所有力量的列表
Just take a few seconds to look through them.
花点时间将它们看一遍
And ask yourself: who are you? When it comes to these strengths.
问自己 说到这些力量时 你是谁
OK.Here's what we are going to do.
好 接下来我们要做的
What we are going to do now
我们现在要做的是
is I'm going to introduce you to two exercises.
我要向你们介绍两个练习
Two exercises that build on the VIA,
两个建立于VIA上的练习
that build on this questionnaire,
建立于这个问卷之上
that build on your identifying your personal character strengths.
建立于你们对自己的个人人格力量的认知之上
The first exercise you are actually going to be doing-
你们要做的第一个练习是
that's next week,for your response paper.
是下周你们的作业中要做的
The second exercise is one that I highly recommend doing-
第二个练习我非常推荐大家做
for lack of time,we can't also do that.
但由于时间关系不能一起做了
The first one- and this is based on research,
第一个练习 基于
done by Peterson and his colleagues-
Peterson和他的同事所做的研究的结果
has been showing remarkable effects,remarkable consequences
对于幸福和成功
in terms of well being as well as in terms of success.
具有显著效果和影响
And what it is about is building capacity.
它是关于建立能力的
It's about identifying the character strengths
关于找到人格力量
and then pursuing them.
然后不断追求它们
Just a quick recap about what it means to build capacity.
再简要概括一下什么叫建立能力
You see,when you are thinking about character strength
当你在考虑以及
and applying character strength,what we know is that
应用人格力量时 我们所知道的是
it helps you become happier- remember a self-concordant journey.
它可以使你有一个更快乐的 自我和谐的旅程
So you found doing something
比如你发现做某事
and constantly engaged in learning new things,
并持续不断地学习新鲜事物
if it is my personal strength or expressing gratitude constantly,
是我的人格力量 或者表达感恩
if that is my character strength.
是我的人格力量
Something that I'm inclined to do.I'll be happier.
是我喜欢做的事 那我就会更快乐
In other words,
换句话说
going back to our model from our second or third class.
回到我们第二或第三节课上讲的模型
It will help us go from zero to the positive.
它可以帮助我们从零走向正
However,what was found in the research is that
然而 这项研究发现的是
it doesn't only help us go from the zero to the positive,
它不仅能使我们从零走向正
it also helps us better deal with the negative.
而且能使我们更好的处理负
This- it does directly.This- it does indirectly.
这是直接的 这是间接的
How? By building capacity.
怎么做到的呢 通过建立能力
If you think about it,this is what positive psychology is about,
如果你仔细想想 这正是积极心理学所要做的
as we've discussed numerous times.
正如我们已经讲过很多次了
It's about building capacities.
是关于建立能力的
It's about strengthening our immune system,
是增强我们的免疫系统
making us more resilient.
使我们适应性更强
Or the other analogy that we use: building a stronger motor
或者用另一个类比 造一个强劲的马达
so that we can better deal with hardships,
从而使我们更好的处理困难
with uphill battles,when these arise.
处理艰难的逆境
So cultivating our VIA directly affects our journey-
因此培养VIA直接影响我们的奋斗过程
we enjoy it more.
我们更乐在其中
From the zero to the positive.And then it does something else.
从零到正 然后它还有别的作用
It also helps us build capacity
它还帮助我们建立能力
so we are better able to deal the negative,with difficulties,
这样我们就能更好地面对消极 面对困难
with the hardships when these inevitably arise.
面对可能出现的逆境
So here is the process:
过程是这样的
the first step is to identify your character strengths.
第一步是找到你的人格力量
Seems pretty obvious.
显而易见的
The way to do it- two steps,two sub-steps.
而找到力量的方法 又分为两步
First,to take the questionnaire,to take the test.
首先 做问卷 做测试
This is the website.It will all be emailed to you plus.
这就是那个网站 我会将它发给你们
It's on the powerpoint.To take this test.It's 240 questions.
是用Powerpoint做的 做这个问卷 共240道题
It should take you about 30 minutes.
可能花半个小时的时间
And there are no right or wrong answers.
没有正确或错误的答案
It's not like "it's better to have awe in your top five
不是像"你最好把敬畏列在前五
and not so great to have prudence as your top one",
最好不要把审慎列为第一"之类的
which by the way is my top value.
顺便说一句 我把审慎列为第一
There's no good,bad.It's identifying who you are.
没有好或者不好 只是识别出你是谁
And all of them,again,we all have all 24.
它们所有 我们都有24个
You know,I think gratitude is my 19th.
感激是排在我的第19位的
Now does that mean that I don't enjoy being grateful,
这是不是意味着我不喜欢感恩
that the gratitude exercise that I do every day
我每天所进行的感恩对我来说
is not beneficial to me? Of course it is!
都是没有好处的呢 当然不是
But much higher for me is the love of learning.
但排得更靠前的是我对学习的热爱
So take the online test.
所以做做这个网上测试
Identify from there your ten top ones- they recommend top five.
找到你的前十 他们推荐前五位
I recommend anywhere between 8 and 12.
我推荐前八位到十二位
And take these 8 to 12 strengths.Read their descriptions-
找到这8种或12种力量 读读它们的描述
what they mean,what they are about,what they say about you.
它们是什么意思 有什么含义 说明了你的什么特质
And then ask yourself: which ones,which five-
然后问问你自己 这里面哪五个
or it could be four,or it could be six,but more or less five-
或四个 或者也可以是六个 大约是五个
which five fulfill the criteria that we discussed earlier?
哪五个符合我们之前讲过的标准
Namely,which are the real me? Or which ones,
也就是 什么是真正的我 或者哪些
when I'm engaging them I feel more energized and motivated?
最能让我感觉到充满活力 充满动力
Or which ones do I grow and develop most from?
或者哪些最能使我成长发展
And from these 8 to 12 strengths,
从这8到12种力量中
identify 4 to 6 that most fulfill these strengths criteria.
找出4到6种符合这些标准的力量
And then choose any one of the character strengths
然后从中任意选择一个
from your final list and apply it,
并应用它
meaning every day for the following 7 days- and again,
也就是接下来一周七天的每一天
this will be your task for the next week-
这会是你们下周的任务
apply these character strengths.
来应用这些人格力量
Every day for the 7 days after that-
这七天之后的时间
that will be up to you and hopefully you will cultivate a ritual,
就看你自己了 希望你们能将其转化为一种例行公事
a habit out of it,apply the next character strength
一种习惯 然后再应用下一项人格力量
or the same character strength in a different way.
或者还是同一种 但用不同的方式
So let me give you a personal example.
给你们举一个个人例子
The third time when I taught positive psychology,
我第三次教积极心理学时
about half way through the semester,
学期到了一半时
I started to feel a little bit enervated,a little bit tired.
我开始觉得有点疲倦 有点精疲力竭
You know,I've done it twice before.
我之前已经教了两次
I knew what I was going to say.I've heard myself say it before.
我知道自己会说什么 我听过自己以前说过
And I thought I lost a little bit of energy,
我觉得我失去了精力
a little bit ongf in teaching.
失去了教学的动力
And then I went back to the VIA.
然后我就回到VIA
And I said "well that made a lot of sense."
我说"这倒确实说得通"
Because my second strength after prudence is love of learning.
因为我在审慎之后排第二位的是对学习的热爱
And when I am teaching the same course,
而当我反复教同一门课时
again,I wasn't learning that much new.
我就没怎么学新东西
So yes,I had new learnings in office hours.
确实我在工作时能学新东西
I always learn a lot- those who've been to my office hours know
我经常在学习 那些来过我办公室的人就知道
that I jot down ideas as we are speaking.
我们说话时我会写下一些想法
But as a whole,in a class,I was doing the same thing.
但总体来说 在这门课上我教的是一样的东西
And then I said,"OK.So I am going to engage in this exercise."
然后我就说"好吧 那我就要实践一下这个练习"
And for me,
对我来说
that exercise was let's take love of learning and continue it,
这个练习就是继续追求对学习的热爱
even when I am teaching the same course.
即便我是在教同样的课
I'm incredibly busy even if I am teaching the same course.But
即使我教同一门课 我还是很忙
I still put in an hour aside every day to learning something new,
但我仍然每天抽一小时出来做点新鲜的事
to reading something that I haven't read before.
阅读一些我没读过的东西
And what that did for me immediately within two days-
而两天之后就对我起了效果
it brought back my energy.
我的能量回来了
It had a trickle effect on other areas,such as my teaching.
它对其他领域产生了涓滴效应 例如我的教学
Because I was reading something new
因为我阅读了新鲜事物
and then it also helped me teach better-
它帮助我更好地教学
not only in terms of energy,
不仅仅是带回了活力
but also new ideas,such as I introduce once in a while.
而且给我的课堂带来了新的想法
Sometimes I tell you I just read this book
有时我会告诉你们我刚读了这本书
and here is what I read.
我读到了这些内容
And I do it constantly even though I am very busy.
即使我很忙我也一直这样做
Because I know that that's very important for well being,
因为我知道这对于幸福
for the ultimate currency as well as for success,for performance
对于终极目标 对于成功都非常重要
So apply whatever it is,whatever
所以不管是什么
your top strengths are consciously until it becomes a habit.
不管你排名第一的力量是什么 都应用它直至它成为习惯
And then- this will also be part of your exercise-
然后 这也将是你们练习的一部分
each night describe how you use your strength on that day
每天晚上描述你当天如何应用了你的力量
and then commit to the next day:
然后用它规划第二天
what are you going to do tomorrow? Why?
你明天要做什么 为什么
Because that reinforces the neural pathways.
因为这能加强你的神经通路
Remember when we describe something good.
请记住这一点
In many ways,the VIA to the DSM is like PPEO to PTSD.
某种程度上说 VIA之于DSM就像PPEO之于PTSD
Remember that? That could be a GRE question.
还记得吗 这可以作为一道GRE题
The analogy is PPEO- positive,
这个类比是PPEO-积极
PTSD- negative is the same as the VIA compared to the DSM.
PTSD-消极 VIA和DSM相比较也是同理
The equivalence-
等价于
positive psychology and conventional psychopathology.
积极心理学以及传统精神病理学
So here is the second exercise after you do this.
这是之后的第二个练习
You could also apply for problem solving.
你可以将其应用于解决问题
Because in a sense,while the VIA indirectly builds capacity
因为在VIA间接地建立能力
and helps us deal with problems,with difficulties,with uphills,
帮助我们面对问题 困难和逆境的同时
we can also use it to affect our difficulties,
我们也可以用它来影响这些困难
to help us with our problems directly.
来直接的帮助我们解决问题
So for example.The first step- same as the previous one.
比方说  第一步 和前面一样
You first identify your character strengths by taking the test,
你首先通过做测验 看看这些力量是否符合标准
by asking what are the criteria the these strengths fulfill.
来找到你的人格力量
And then,identify any problem,whether it's in personal life,
然后找到你的问题 不论是在个人生活
whether it's in,on the sports field,
或者是在运动方面
whether it's on,in a relationship,whether it's at work.
或者是情感方面 或者工作方面
Identify certain problem that you want to deal with.
找出你想要解决的问题
And then ask how you can apply one of the character,
然后问问自己如何能够应用其中一种
or some of the character strengths toward that problem.
或几种力量来解决这个问题
So for example.Let's take an example.
举个例子
Let's say one of the problem that I face
比如说我遇到的一个
is that I am mostly avoiding.
我极力避免的问题
I am afraid of taking risks.I don't put myself on the line.
我害怕冒险 我不会不顾一切
Because I am anxious and afraid.
因为我很焦虑 并且害怕
And love of learning is one of our strengths.
而对学习的热爱是我的一种力量
What I can do is use the love of learning to deal with my phobia,
我所能做的就是用对学习的热爱来处理我的
my anxiety,my fear of putting myself on the line.
恐惧 焦虑 和害怕
How? By learning all I can learn about
怎么做呢 通过学习任何有关
how to better deal with phobia and anxiety,
如何更好地解决焦虑和恐惧的知识
which by the way is exactly what I did.
我也正是这样做的
Read every book I could find.
阅读任何我能找到的书
Talked to any person who I thought knew about it.
和我认为了解这方面的人聊天
Used the strength
利用这个力量
and then applied it to what had been a weakness of mine.
将其应用于我的弱点
Or relationships.
人际关系也一样
Let's say we are going through a difficulty in relationship.
比如说我们的人际关系正面临一定的困难
And one of my top strengths is for example,authenticity.
而我的力量之一 比方说是真诚可靠
And then how can I use my authenticity
那我如何将我的可靠
in my interactions with my partner-
用于我和我伙伴之间的关系
and that will lead to higher levels of intimacy
最终达到更高层次的亲密
and improve the relationship in the long run,
长远来看 改善我们间的关系
which is exactly what I did.
我也正是这样做的
One of my top strengths-
将我的力量
and applied it to cultivating more intimacy.
应用于产生更加亲密的关系
Think of your own example.
想想你们自己的例子
Again,this will not be a response paper,
这不是作业
but I highly recommend and urge you to apply it.
但我十分推荐你们试试
Let's put some of these ideas together.
让我们来汇总一下这些概念
Let's look at the decisions that some of you are making right now
让我们看看你们现在或者将来
or will be making in the future,
会做的决定
whether it's next year or three years from now,
无论是明年 或是三年之后
or 20 or 40 years from now.
或者20年 40年以后
How do you make decisions and how do you-
你如何去做决定
what may be a helpful framework
什么是制定一个自我和谐的奋斗过程
for identifying a self-concordant journey as well as outcome?
以及目标的有效框架呢
And one of the ways to do it
其中一种方法
is by looking at the work of Amy Wrzesniewski
就是看看Amy Wrzesniewski的研究
that I do talk about in the work chapter,
我在之前的课上讲过
but still worth going over again.
但还是值得反复再提
About work orientation.
关于工作方向的研究
And this is going to apply not just to work.
这不仅适用于工作
It can apply to other areas in our lives.
也适用于我们生活的其他方面
Generally what Wrzesniewski and others found is that
Wrzesniewski他们发现的是
people's perception of work
人们对于工作的概念
can be classified into three categories.
可以分为三类
Some people perceive their work as a job; others as a career;
有些人认为他们的工作是工作 有的人认为是职业
and yet,others,not the majority unfortunately,
还有一些人 但很不幸不是多数
hopefully in the future the majority-
希望在将来成为多数
some people perceive it as a calling.
有些人认为它是一种使命
Primarily it doesn't mean that
这并不意味着
the person who perceives his or her work
将工作视为使命的人
as a calling does not sometimes experience it as a job.
就不会时不时觉得这只是工作
However,overall,they perceive their work
但总体而言 他们认为他们的工作
as a calling versus a career versus a job.
是一种使命 而非职业或仅仅是工作
And you can distinguish them by looking at the following criteria
你可以用以下标准来区分出他们
what motivates them- what keeps them going,
他们的动力是什么 是什么让他们持续努力
what pushes and pulls them; what do they perceive work as-
什么推动或拉着他们 他们如何理解工作
what is their interpretation of the workplace;
他们如何诠释工作的地方
what do they expect- what are they hoping for; and finally,
他们的期待是什么 最后
what are they looking forward to in the future in that work.
他们对这份工作的未来所寄望的是什么
So people who perceive their work as a job: motivation- paycheck
那些将工作仅仅视为工作的人 他们的动力是
at the end of the month or the end of the week;
每个月末 或者每个周末的工资
work as something I have to do- it's a chore,
工作是我不得不做的事 它是琐事
I have no choice about it; what do they expect- nothing much;
我别无选择 他们期待什么呢 没有什么
they look forward to TGIF or the holiday,the break,
他们期待星期五 期待放假休息
the end of the semester,the end of the two year period,
期待学期结束 期待两年研究生结束
or whatever it may be.
或者之类的
The career perception,orientation:
而将工作视为职业的
money and advancement are what motivates these individuals,
薪酬和晋升是他们的动力
getting to the next stage;
不断地升职
work as- it's a race,a race to the top-
工作就像赛跑 跑到最高处
this is what the rat racers mostly reside;
这是好胜者常有的情况
the expectation- more prestige,more power,more money,
他们的期望是 更多的特权 更强的力量 更多的钱
more prestige,more power,again,advancement,attainment,
更多的特权 更强的力量 晋升 升职
achievement of the next goal;
不断地成就
and they are looking forward to the next promotion.
他们寄望的是不断的升职
And this applies to different areas- it could be
这也同样于其他领域 比如说
from PreMed to Med school to internship at the best place,
从医学预科到医学院 到最好的医院的实习
to the chief,head of the department,
到主治医生 到部门负责人
to the chief of the hospital.
再到医院院长
It could be the race from being analyst to an associate to a partner
可以是从分析师 到合作人 到合伙人
It could be the race from being
也可以是从助手到
an assistant to an associate to a full professor.
副教授 再到正教授
It can apply to any area,the red race.
这种竞争适用于各个领域
The lucky few who perceive their work as calling:
而那些幸运地将工作视为使命的少数人
the motivation is the thing in itself-
他们的动力来自于工作本身
it's about self-concordant goal,
是一种自我和谐的目标
it's also about self-concordant journey;
是自我和谐的奋斗过程
how do they perceive work- it's a mission,it's a vocation,
他们怎么理解工作 他们认为这是种任务 是种使命
it's what they are meant to be doing,it's what
他们本就该做这个
they want to be doing more than anything else in the world.
做这件事比起所有其他事都更乐意
They see it not as a chore,but it's a privilege to be engaged in
他们不认为这是琐事 能够参与其中
what it is that they are doing.
就是一种特权
The expectations- their mission: a better world.
他们的期望 也是他们的使命 是使世界更美好
And finally,what do they look forward to- more work.
而最后 他们寄望的是更多的工作
More work where they can actualize themselves,
从而他们能实现自身
where they can fulfill themselves,
成就自身
where they can be- to use the military cliche- all they can be.
引用军事名言 可以成为任何他们想成为的人
Now when you look at this,
讲到这个
it's mostly impossible to experience a sense of calling
要在每时每刻都感觉到召唤或使命
and mission and a self-concordant journey every hour of the day.
以及自我和谐的旅程是不太可能的
Just like it's not possible to be happy
就像不可能总是能够
and to experience constantly experience that constant high.
体验到这么多的快乐
You know,for example,teaching is my calling.
举个例子 教学就是我的使命
I certainly experience a sense of calling-
我感受到了召唤
it's the thing in itself; it's what I want to do professionally
来自于这件事本身 我做这件事
more than anything else in the world.
比所有其他事更乐意
At the same time,
同时
there are elements of teaching that I don't enjoy it as much.
教学中也有很多我不喜欢的东西
And I do feel that I fell a little bit toward
我也确实偶尔会感觉到
"well,this is my job- I had to do it" such as
"这是我的工作 我必须要做"的感觉
going over my lecture notes five times before each lecture.
比如每次上课前备五遍课
The first time,pretty interesting;
第一遍非常有趣
you know second and third it gets a little bit repetitive.
第二遍第三遍就有点重复了
But I know if I want to produce a good and effective lecture-
但我知道如果我要把课讲好
because that is my calling,teaching,
因为教学是我的使命
I have to go over it many times.
我必须要反复备课
And I can tell the difference
我也能感受到
when I go over it once or twice versus five times.
备一两遍课和备五遍的区别
So that's important to me.
所以这对我来说很重要
But that part of my work-
但这时我的工作
it is a chore,something that I have to do.
就是种琐事 我不得不做的事
However,remember the trickle effect.
然而 记住涓滴效应
Because overall,there's a sense of calling.
由于整体来说 这是种使命
Overall,it's a self-concordant goal as well as journey.
整体来说 这是自我和谐的目标及过程
Even those parts are OK,not that bad.
所以即使备五遍课也没问题 也没那么糟
Or let's say you really enjoy a certain course.
或者比方说你很喜欢一门课
Let's take a hypothetical example,1504.
假设是1504
And another hypothetical example,
再做个假设
you happen to have a midterm in a week.
你一周后就要期中考了
You know,you may not enjoy every step of the way.
你可能不会享受其中每一步
You know going over the material
比如把书看两遍
for the second time or third time.
或者看三遍
However,if overall that experience is self-concordant,
但如果整体来说这件事是自我和谐的
important to you,and you enjoy it,
对你来说很重要 你很喜欢
even that part will not be that bad.It will be OK,
那么那样也就没那么糟糕 是可以接受的
especially if you start seeing that during that process,
尤其是当你发现在这个过程中
you'll begin to make new connections,
你建立了新的联系
understand things,important things about yourself.
理解了你觉得很重要的知识
Important thing also to keep in mind about calling is that
关于使命同样要记住的一点是
well it does depend to some extent
它确实从某种程度上取决于
on the kind of work that you do.
你工作的种类
It depends much more on your perception of the work.
但更取决于你对工作的理解
So the research that I talk about in the book
我在书里讲到的研究
is about cleaners in a hospital
是关于医院里的清洁工的
who were able to see their work as a calling.
他们将他们的工作视为使命
Why? Because they interpret their work not as
为什么 因为他们不是将工作诠释成
"I have to pick up the garbage and clean the toilet"-
"我必须清扫垃圾 打扫厕所"
which they actually had to do,but more as
虽然这是他们实际的工作 而是
"I'm taking care of these patients; because without my work,
"我在照顾这些病人 没有我的努力
without me doing the excellent work,there'll be more pollution
没有我这些出色的工作 就会产生更大的污染
and more people hurt in the hospital.
医院里会有更多人受害"
And these people who perceive-
而这些人
these cleaners who perceive their work
这些将工作理解为使命的
had the calling orientation were much more likely to engage
清洁工会更愿意
in a conversation with the patients in the hospital,
和医院里的病人聊天
were much more likely to help.
更愿意伸出援手
And interestingly,many doctors from this same hospital
有趣的是 同一家医院里的很多医生
perceive their work as a job.
将他们的工作仅仅视为工作
Now you are more likely,again- not good,not bad it is-
你会更容易 同样没有好坏之分
you are more likely to find a sense of calling in your work
你会更容易在工作中找到使命感
if you are a leader versus the janitor
如果你在单位里是领导
or the cleaning person in an organization.It's more likely.
而不是门卫 或者清洁工 会更容易感受到
However,that does not mean that the person
但这并不代表
who cleans the hospital cannot find the calling
打扫医院的人就不能找到使命感
and there are many examples.
有很多这样的例子
And the examples that Wrzesniewski talks about in the research
Wrzensniewski在研究中给出的例子
are things such as comparing between cleaners and other cleaners,
就是比较这些清洁工和其他清洁工
calling versus chore,between certain hair dressers
比较使命和琐事 以及比较将工作
to see their work as a chore versus ones who see it as a calling.
视为琐事的和将其视为使命的发型师
I'm sure that you had your haircut with your,
我相信你们都
with certain hair dressers who really do see it as a calling.
被将理发视为使命的发型师剪过头发
I mean there are more psychologists than hair dressers.
我的意思是心理学家比理发师要多
Or engineers.Some just see their work-
或者工程师 有的觉得他们的工作是
"OK.I have to do this.That's all I think about."
"好吧 这是我不得不做的事 就这样吧"
Versus thinking about a bigger picture.
有的则从更大的角度来考虑
I'm not just a cog in a mill.I'm part of an important project.
我不是无足轻重的 我是一个很重要的项目的一部分
We can perceive almost any work
我们可以将所有对工作的理解
as falling into one of these three categories.
都归于这三类
Think about investment bank-
想想投资银行
I know many of you are going into investment banking.
我知道你们中很多人都想去投资银行
One of the ways to perceive investment banking is
一种理解投资银行的方式是
"you know I'm going there.I'm going to make a big load of money.
"我要去那儿 我要赚大把大把的钱
And I'm going to have a great life style."
过上舒适的生活"
And that is an important motivation.Again,
这是种很重要的动力
people aren't and shouldn't be impervious to material comfort.
人们不应该完全抵制物质上的舒适
That's OK.However,people who only look at that,who only look-
没有关系 然而仅仅这样只看到这个的人
"OK.It's going to give me a great life style.
"这能让我过上很好的生活
I'm going to send my kids to the best schools- it's a good thing
我要送我的孩子去最好的学校 这挺好的
and I'm going to live in a beautiful neighborhood,
我要住在漂亮的社区里
a beautiful house and a big car- have a lot of prestige."
有一所漂亮的房子和一辆豪华的车 有很多的特权"
Again,human nature.These needs- it's fine.
这是人性 这些需求都是正常的
But people who just look at these things will not be happy,
但仅仅看到这些的人不会快乐
or will not live up to their potential happiness in the long run.
或者不会长期地快乐
However,if I look at investment banking as that
但如果不仅看到投资银行的这些方面
and also an opportunity to create jobs which it does do-
还看到它创造岗位的机会 而它确实如此
JP Morgan and all the investment bankers
JP Morgan和他之后的
who came up after him have created millions and millions of jobs
所有投资银行家 创造了成千上万的岗位
that would not have existed without investment banking.
在投资银行业出现前都不存在的岗位
But investment banking
而投资银行
is also about lubricating the wheels of economy,that
也能润滑经济的齿轮
it will also provide an opportunity to then go and contribute,
能够提供机会 使得你能够继续
whether it's financially
不管从经济上
or for my knowledge to Not for Profit organizations.
还是知识上 奉献于非营利组织
Because today what Not for Profit organizations need most
因为当今许多非营利组织最需要的
is effective sound professional fiscal policies.
就是有效 健全 专业的财政政策
Which you'll learn as an investment banker
而这正是你作为投资银行家
or a consultant or whatever it is.
或者顾问 所能学到的
Now some people say,"you are rationalizing
有的人说"你这样看待投资银行
if you look at the investment banking as all these things."
是在给自己找借口"
You are not rationalizing.
你并不是在找借口
You know what you are doing? You are simply looking at reality.
你知道你所做的是什么吗 你只是看到了事实
Things that are real,that are there- they are not invented.
真实的事情 不是人为制造出来的
But most people do not see them,
但很多人看不到它们
just like most people did not see the children on the bus.
就像很多人看不到公车上的孩子
And when you don't see something as far as you're concerned,
而如果你看不见它 那么你就会认为
it doesn't exist.
它不存在
And for most investment bankers,
对于很多投资银行家来说
they burn out because they don't also- not only,
他们最终筋疲力竭因为他们没有
but they don't also see the positive components of that work-
没有看到这份工作的积极部分
components that certainly can fall under a calling.
如果将其当成使命就一定能看到的部分
Again,most works,
许多工作
whether it's working in a hospital and taking care of cleanliness
无论是在医院做清洁工作
whether it's working as a medical doctor,
或者是作为一个医生
whether it's working as an investment banker,
或者是成为投资银行家
as a teacher,as a volunteer,as monk- whatever it is,
成为老师 志愿者 和尚 不管是什么
can be perceived as job,can be perceived as a career,
都能被理解为工作 也能被理解为职业
and can be perceived a calling.
也可以被理解为使命
And very often the choice is up to you.How do you interpret it?
通常选择权都在于你 你怎么诠释它
Abraham Maslow: "It is certainly true that
Abraham Maslow说"没错
many of us evade our constitutionally suggested vocations
我们许多人回避了我们天生的职业
(call,destiny,task in life,mission).
(使命 命运 天命 职责)
So often we run away from the responsibilities dictated
因此我们经常逃脱了一些本性
(or rather suggested) by nature,by fate,
命运所指定(或者说暗示)的责任
even sometimes by accident,
即使有时是意外的
just as Jonah tried-in vain-to run away from his fate."
就像Jonah试图逃离他的命运 最终失败了一样"
What is your fate? What is your calling? What is your destiny?
你的命运是什么 使命是什么 天命是什么
Just listen to the voice that suggests your vocation.
听从暗示你天命的那个声音
Just listen to the call that guides you to your calling.
听从指引你使命的召唤
What is it? You know the problem is
它是什么 问题在于
we don't take time to think about these questions.
我们没有花时间来思考这些问题
Sometimes because we are afraid of the answer.
有时是因为我们害怕得到答案
Because what if it is teaching?
万一你想去教书呢?
You know,what about all the pressure
而所有来自外界的压力
that I feel from the outside to go and be a consultant?
让你去做顾问怎么办
Or what if it is investment banking? What about the pressure
或者万一是投资银行呢
that I hear from my friends and colleagues who say
而来自朋友和同事的压力说
"well you should do something else"-
"你应该做点别的"
more "noble" with your Harvard education.
用你的哈佛文凭去找更好的工作时的压力
The most noble thing is to listen to that inner voice.
最好的工作就是听从你的内心
Because when we pursue our passions.
因为当我们追求自己热爱的事业时
When we pursue a self-concordant goal
当我们追求自我和谐的目标
and a self-concordant journey,that's when we come alive
和自我和谐的奋斗过程时 我们才能真正地活着
and that's when we also make the world a better place.
才能将世界变得更美好
Remember Gandhi: "Be the change you want to see in the world."
甘地说过"你必须成为你希望看到的改变"
And if you want a happier world,begin with yourself.
如果你想让世界更快乐 就要从自己做起
Easier said than done.
说起来容易做起来难
But it's probably the most important question
但这可能是你要问你自己的
that you can ask of yourself.
最重要的问题
And by the way,that answer may change.
而答案是有可能改变的
It may be one thing today
今天可能是这样
and be something different two and a half years from now.
两年半后可能就不一样了
And it may be very different 22 and a half years from now.
二十二年半后可能又完全不一样
Or 50 years from now.
或者五十年后
But asking this question- when we really,
但问这个问题 如果我们真正地
truly ask this question,we open up possibilities
问自己这个问题 就有了可能性
and see things that we may have not seen before.
能看到我们以前看不到的东西
Our- metaphorically speaking,children on the bus.
打个比方 看到了公车上的孩子
Our fate.Our destiny.Our vocation.Our calling.
我们的命运 天命 职责 使命
I think it was captured best-
我觉得将这一点
this whole idea by one of the students
概括得最好的是
who sat where you are sitting just two years ago,
两年前坐在你们现在坐的地方的一个学生
also one of the cofounders of Women in Business,
也是《商业中的女性》的创办人之一
Ambani Carter: Instead of focusing on what we can live with,
Ambani Carter 她说"我们不应专注于生命中可以拥有的
we should be thinking about what we can't live without."
而应想到那些我们生命中不可或缺的
What can't you live without? What are you about?
少了什么你活不下去 你需要什么
Our next topic related to goals,
我们的下一话题 关于目标
related to what we discussed last time
关于我们上次讲到的
is something that I'm sure none of you can relate to,
我相信你们没有一个人能想到
something that is completely foreign to you
这对于你和你身边的朋友来说
and your friends sitting around you.
都是非常陌生的
And that is not what I expected to come up on this screen,
就是... 我没预料到会出现这样的情况
but soon we will get to that topic,I promise.
但很快我们就会讲到的 我保证
Just a few- before we move on to that very important topic,
在我们进入那个非常重要的话题之前
I just want to build tension.It was all planned of course.
我只是想制造气氛 这都是设计好的
Before we get to that topic,just a few tips about setting goals.
在我们进入那个话题之前 讲讲制定目标的一些建议
Some basic ones.
非常基本的建议
First,write them down.
首先 要把它们写下来
You know writing them down is making a commitment,
写下来就是做一种承诺
much more of a commitment than just saying them even.
比起只是把它们说出来
It's better to say them publicly
最好是公开地把它们说出来
than just to say them just to ourselves or think about them.
而不是只说给自己听 或者只是想想
But writing them down makes a difference.
但把它们写下来完全不同
A lot of research showing the effect of making plans,
很多研究都显示了制定计划
lists and writing goals.
列出并写下目标的作用
Second,set lifelines.
其次 制定最早期限
You know people talk about deadlines.
很多人都会说"最后期限"
Tammy,my wife says,"I think it's much more effective,
我的妻子Tammy说"我觉得制定最早期限
much more useful to set lifelines."
会更有效 更有帮助"
Dates by which we hope to achieve those certain goals.
也就是我们希望完成这些目标的日期
Why lifelines? Because goals,
为什么要制定最早期限呢 因为目标
especially self-concordant goals are about inspiring us.
尤其是自我和谐的目标是可以激励我们的
In other words,putting the spirit inside us.
换句话说 给我们注入活力
They are about making our life happier.
它们使我们的生活更快乐
More energetic.So lifelines.Setting goals.Very important.
更具有活力 因此要制定最早期限 制定目标 这非常重要
It's not I-will-do-the-following-soonish;
不是"我马上就做这些事"
it's "I will do the following by the first of July,2009.
而是"我在2009年7月1日前做好这些事"
Connected to this- making them specific.
加上日期 使它们细化
In other words,it's not I'm going to improve sales pretty soon,
换言之 不是说我马上 或者很快就会
or very quickly,but rather-
提升销量 而是
I'm going to increase sales 5 percent by December 31,2008.
我会在2008年12月31日前使销量增加5%
Specific lifeline as well as specific project.
具体的最早期限 以及具体的目标
Also,let's say that I want to become fit.
同样 比如说我想健身
It's not just the generic "I want to become fitter";
不是一般的"我想要更苗条健康"
it's rather "I'm going to run 5 miles,
而是"我要在2008年10月15日前
4 times a week by October 15,2008." Concrete.Specific.
每周跑四次步 每次5英里" 明确 具体的目标
Remember what we talked about-
我们讲过
the most important thing about goals is not achieving those goals
制定目标最重要的不是在于完成这些目标
It's not that is what would make us happy or sad
不是说我们会因为完成就感到高兴
if we do or don't achieve them.
或者没完成就悲伤
The key is to energize us,to motivate us,to liberate us,
其关键在于给予我们能量 给予我们动力 使我们自由
to contribute as a means toward the end-
是通往最终目的的一种方式
the end being the journey.
而最终目的是过程本身
The goals that facilitate the journey best or goals
是那些最有助于这个过程的目标或者
that we actually have-
我们所拥有的
not all goals,but some goals- 50 percent of achieving.
不是所有 但一部分 完成了一半的目标
It's the goals such as Kennedy set in 1962,
就像肯尼迪在1962年提出的目标
"we will reach the moon by the end of the decade,"
"我们要在这十年中登上月球"
at the time when the metal that
而那时能够忍受
was necessary to withstand the heat of getting out of the space
飞到外太空以及回到地球所产生的高温的
and coming back to earth was not even invented.
金属都还没发明出来
It was at a time
那时他们
when they did not have the technology on numerous levels to send,
都还没有能将人送往月球
to land a person on the moon.
并使其着陆的技术
And yet,he declared that goal that
然而他宣布了这个目标
"by the end of the decade,we will do it." It energized NASA-
"十年内我们要做到" 这给予了NASA动力
some people thought he was crazy,but it energized them.
有些人觉得他疯了 但它确实给予了他们动力
And you know,after 1969,
而在1969年后
NASA experienced a real drop in their motivation,
NASA动力严重减少
in their passion.Until essentially the mid 80s.
热情急剧减退 一直持续到80年代中期
Because they didn't have a similar inspiring goal.
因为他们没有类似的激励性的目标了
We see it also in the individual level.
在个人水平上同样可以看到
And I talked about it in the book,
我在书里也说道
where people had goals and then did not achieve these goals,
当人们有了目标而没有实现这些目标
or achieve these goals and did not set new goals.
或者实现了目标却没有制定新目标时
And they felt enervated,and very often,uninspired.
他们就会感到精疲力竭 失去动力
Stretch goals.
要明确目标
Ellen Langer did the following research:
Ellen Langer做了以下研究
bringing in a group of people
聚集一组人
and introduce them to highly successful scientists and inventors.
将他们介绍给成功的科学家和发明家
And she asked them-
然后告诉他们
these were you know world famous,world class performers-
这些是世界知名的科学家
and she asked these individuals,
然后她让这些人
these students to assess these very successful individuals
让这些学生评估这些成功人士
and then to say,"how likely are you to reach their level?"
然后问"你觉得你有多大可能达到他们的水平"
And they assess them extremely highly.
然后他们给了这些人非常高的评价
They respect them.They admire them.
尊重他们 敬仰他们
And they said that they are unlikely to achieve their level.
说自己永远达不到他们的水平
And then,she brought a second group of students
然后她又召集了另一群学生
and she got them to look at the exact same individuals-
带他们去见同样的人
same highly successful scientists,inventors,
同一批非常成功的科学家 发明家
people who really made it with one difference.
一个举动改变世界的人
She also introduced some of the characteristics
她还介绍了他们走向成功之路的
of their path toward greatness.
一些过程和特点
For example,failures on the way.
比如说经历的失败
Insecurity.Disappointments.Hardships.
不安 失望 坎坷
And how they actually got from point A to point B.
以及他们最终是怎样从这边跨越到另一边的
And she asked them to evaluate them.
然后她让他们评价这些成功人士
And they respected them highly,just as much.
他们同样给了这些人很高的评价
And when she asked
而当她问
"how likely are you to achieve those goals," - much more likely.
"你觉得你有多大可能达到他们的水平"时 回答则是有可能
And as we know,beliefs are self-fulfilling prophecies.
我们都知道 信仰是自我实现的预言
No.1 predictor of long term success.
长期成功的最佳预言者
In addition- the John Carlton research,
此外 是John Carlton做的研究
in addition to constantly asking questions,
除了不断地问问题
it's believing that you can do well.
重要的是相信你能做到
And if we only look at the outcome and not the journey,
如果我们只看结果不看过程
we are much less likely to believe that
我们比较不容易相信
we can attain this outcome.
我们能取得这样的结果
Breaking down successes.
使成功破灭
Langer said,"People can imagine themselves taking steps,
Langer说"人们能想象到自己的每一步
while great heights seem entirely forbidden."
但却觉得高峰是难以攀登的"
Have a long term goal
制定一个长期目标
and then break it down to short term or medium term goal.
然后将其拆分为短期或者中期的目标
Short term goal.
短期目标
And then make plans and then create rituals based on these plans.
然后制定计划 基于这些计划建立习惯
Step by step.Breaking down achievement.
一步一步来 将成功细化
Much more likely to believe that's possible
就会更容易相信那是可能的
and consequently much more likely to actually get there.
也就更容易确实到达那个目标
And now ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们
the moment you've all been waiting for.
你们等待已久的时刻
Something that none of you are familiar with.
一些你们都不熟悉的东西
That you may not be able to connect to,
你们可能没有仔细想过
but something that- please indulge me and I'll talk about.
但是是一种... 请让我说完 我会讲的
Stress.So I asked at the beginning of the class
压力 我在课堂开始时问
"who wants to experience less stress".
"有谁想要少点压力的"
Most of you put your hand up.
你们大多数人都举了手
Stress is a global- not American,not Western- global epidemic.
压力是一种全球性的 不仅限于美国或西方社会 而是全球的通病
By the end of this class,
在这节课最后
within 20 minutes,my hope is that we all look like this.
这二十分钟里 我希望我们都像这样
Minus the beer if you are not 21 yet.
如果你们没到21就去掉啤酒
Now the most important thing when dealing with stress-
处理压力最重要的一点
and again,it is a global,very problematic epidemic-
这是一种全球性的严重的流行病
we talk about procrastination.
我们讲到拖延症
This is what I do when I procrastinate.
我出现拖延症时会这样做
I go on Google image and look for things like that.
我去Google图片搜索这样的东西
And I tell myself it's part of your work.
然后告诉自己这是你工作的一部分
It's important.Yeah.
这很重要
It's all about cognitive reframing.
这是关于认知重建的
When dealing with stress,what we need to do is take time out.
在处理压力时 我们所要做的就是抽出点时间
Let me share with you- again,I have talked about this before.
我来和你们分享一下 我以前讲过的
This is from the New England Journal of Medicine,
摘自《新英格兰医学杂志》
an article written by our very own,Richard Kadison.
是由我们学校的Richard Kadison写的一篇文章
He's the head of the mental health services here.
他是本校心理咨询处的负责人
"In a recent national survey of 13,500 college students,
"在一项针对全国13500个大学生的调查中
nearly 45 percent reported being so depressed
近45%表示非常抑郁
that they had difficulty functioning,
以至于没法工作学习
and 94 percent reported feeling overwhelmed
94%表示对于他们做的事
by everything they had to do.”
感到了过大的压力"
45 percent.You know,people,
45%
when they ask me about the class at Harvard-
人们问我哈佛的课程情况
the fact that it's a popular class,they say,
事实上那课程还挺有名的 他们说
"is it because it's Harvard?
"是因为在哈佛吗
Is it because at Harvard there's more stress?" No,there isn't.
是因为在哈佛压力比较大吗" 不是的
In fact,when the Crimson did,ask similar question,
事实上 当Crimson做了类似的调查后
they found at Harvard 47 percent.
他们发现在哈佛是47%
So really,no difference.
所以其实没有区别
Nationwide- regardless of which university,
这是全国性的 不管是哪个大学
which college you go to.
哪个学院
This is startling.I mean,I was shocked.
这非常令人吃惊 我震惊了
I know- I've been on college campus for the last 16 years.
过去16年里我都在大学校园里
I know the situation.But I was even surprised by this number.
我知道情况是怎样 但我还是对这个数字很惊讶
And this is not the regular ups and downs
而且这不是我们平时一天要经历十遍的
that we go through 10 times a day.
正常情绪起伏
This is depression to the point of not functioning.
而是会导致无法工作学习的抑郁
How can we explain it? The 45 percent.
怎么解释这45%呢
By looking at the 94 percent.Let me be more specific.
通过看这94% 让我说得具体一点
You see,students today clearly have too much to do.
可以看到 今天的学生要做的事太多了
When I was a resident tutor in Leverett House,
当我还是Leverett宿舍的一个住校教师
given that my PHD was also from the business school,
因为我的博士学位是商学院的
my role was a pre business tutor.
我当时还是个预备商学教师
So what I did,as many of you know,
所以我当时做的事 你们很多人都知道
was I looked at students' resumes,
我看学生们的简历
the CVs and helped them hone it,
履历 然后帮他们润色
make it better for the recruiting process or other processes
使其更适用于他们找工作的
where they were looking for work.
招聘及其他环节
And it really amazed me that just about every year,
令我非常惊讶的是 每年
just about every year,the resumes became more impressive.
几乎每年 简历都愈发令人印象深刻
Smaller fonts,bigger titles,narrower margins.
字体更小 标题更大 页边距更窄
Each year,you know,very often,the older generation says-
每一年 老一辈进入哈佛的人
who have gone to Harvard- they say,
他们会说
"I wouldn't have got into Harvard today."
"放在今天我肯定进不了哈佛"
It's true! It's unfortunate,but it's true.
确实是这样 很不幸 但这是真的
And I looked at these resumes and I was very impressed.
当我看到这些简历时 感到印象非常深刻
And I said,"wow." Until I noticed a price that students-
我会说"哇" 直到我注意到学生们
you,me- were paying for the smaller fonts and narrower margins.
为了这更小的字体和更窄的页边距所付出的代价
And the price is that we feel overwhelmed,
这代价就是过度紧张不安
too much to do,stress,anxiety.
太多要做的事 压力 焦虑
And as a result of it-
结果导致
and there's a lot of data supporting this error-
有许多数据能支持这一点
as a result of this,higher likelihood of depression.
结果导致了更大可能的抑郁
And this is what we see on college campuses.
这种情况我们时常会在大学校园见到
This is what we see around the country.
会在整个国家各处见到
This is what we see around the world.
会在世界到处见到
Because I recently returned from China-
我最近刚从中国回来
not very different from this.
并没有很大的差别
I recently came from Australia- very similar to this.
我最近也去过澳大利亚 也与此非常相似
Try to fit in too many things in too little time:
在过短的时间内希望完成过多的事
taking more courses,being part of more student organizations.
学更多的课 参加更多的学生社团
And that has...That exacts a price.OK.Here she is.
这是需要付出代价的 这就是她
The psychologist- the one and only Ellen DeGeneres
心理学家 独一无二的Ellen DeGeneres
talking about the state of affairs.
在谈论国家大事
I believe some days sitcoms will be 30 seconds long.
我觉得有一天情景喜剧只需要30秒
Cause that's all we need.
因为我们只需要这么长的时间
That's all our attention span can take.
我们的注意力就只能维持这么长时间
Cause our attention span is short.
因为我们的注意力维持时间很短
We've all got Attention Deficit Disorder
我们都有注意力缺乏症
or ADD or OCD or one of these disorders with three letters
或者说ADD 或者OCD(强迫症) 或者这种三个字母的病
because we don't have the time
因为我们没有时间和
or patience to pronounce the entire disorder.
耐心来把整个病的名字说完
That should be a disorder right there,TBD - too busy disorder.
应该有一个这样的病 TBD-过于忙碌症
The weather is actually the happiest part of the news
天气预报可能是新闻最快乐的部分了
because at some point you're going to hear something positive.
因为你们就能不时听到些积极的东西
You're going to hear"it's a beautiful day".
你们可以听到"今天天气不错"
Or "it's going to be a beautiful day".
或者"今天将会有个好天气"
And it's nice to take in something positive.
听积极的东西总是很好的
Because we hear all these negative stuff all the time
因为我们总是听到那些消极的东西
and we go out into the world so chaotic
我们外面的世界如此混乱
and we're not going to notice it's a beautiful day.
以至于都没办法注意到天气很好
We are moving too fast to even pay atention to that.
我们的节奏太快以至于无法注意到
And we need help to keep up with that pace
我们需要帮助来追赶这节奏
so we put a coffee shop here
所以我们在这建一个咖啡店
and a coffee shop here and a coffee shop here.
这里建一个咖啡店 那里建一个咖啡店
And the smallest coffee is "Tall".And
最小的咖啡店叫"大咖啡"
I'll have a coffee and a side red bull cause I'm very very busy!
我会要一杯咖啡伴一罐红牛 因为我很忙很忙!
I've got TBD and I'm late for yoga..Hurry hurry!
我患了TBD 我的瑜伽课要迟到了 快 快点!
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:TBD should be part of the DSM.Really should be.
TBD应该被收进DSM里
We pay a very high price for this TBD.
我们为这个TBD付出了很高的代价
First of all,psychological health-
首先 心理健康
one of the best predictors of depression.Physical health.
抑郁症最容易导致的后果之一 生理健康
Many doctors estimate about 80 percent of our physical ailments
许多医生估计约80%我们的生理疾病
are result of stress,weaken our immune system.
是由于压力所致 使我们的免疫系统变弱
And finally,today,this year,
最后 当下 今年
the No.1 cause for loss of days at work globally
旷工的最大原因 全球来说
is something related to our psychology,
是关于我们的心理的
whether it's stress,or related emotions,feelings,experiences.
不管是压力 或者情感 感觉 经历
It never used to be that in the past.
过去从没有这样
Today it's psychological reasons.
如今则是因为心理的原因
And we pay a price
我们付出的代价
both in terms of our productivity as well as creativity.
不仅是效率 还有创造力
Think back to the broaden and build theory:
回想拓延-建构理论
when we are stressed,we are more likely to narrow and constrict,
当我们处于压力下时 更容易变得狭隘和约束
as opposed to think outside the box.
相比于在盒子外思考来说
All right.So what do we do with this stress?
好了 那我们该如何处理这种压力呢
What do we do with it? Let's use positive psychology.
该怎么应对呢 让我们应用积极心理学
Because it really is a problem that
因为这确实是我们希望
we want to be able to deal with,
能够解决的问题
that I know,certainly,personally,
至少我个人
it's a problem that I dealt with for very long time.
很早就想解决它了
So the conventional question,
传统的问题
the traditional psychologist question was
传统的心理学家会问
"why are so many people stressed?"
"为什么这么多人压力过大"
An important question,good question,
这是非常重要的 非常好的问题
question that yielded many great answers but not enough.
能够引出很多好的回答 但仍然不够
And then positive psychologists came in.
然后积极心理学出现了
And what they did was ask also the positive question.
而他们所做的是 同样问一些积极地问题
Just like
就像
when we talked about the research with at risk population.
我们在讲到关于危险人群的研究时说过
Just like Marva Collins asked a different question.
就像Marva Collins曾经问过一个不一样的问题
Because questions open up avenues,
因为问题能打开思路
quests that we may have not seen before.
探索我们之前可能没有见过的东西
And the question became "what do those who were successful
这样问题就变成"那些成功的
and able to lead a healthy and happy life do?"
过着健康快乐生活的人是怎么做的"
In other words,focusing on what works.
换句话说 关注起作用的事物
In other words,focusing on tip of the stem.
也就是关注茎尖端的芽
Because while most people are stressed,not all of them are.
因为虽然很多人都压力过大 但不是所有人都这样
There are people who are able to be successful
有一些人能够很成功
and at the same time,lead a health and happy life.
同时过着健康和快乐的生活
What do they do? What is it about them? Here is what they do.
他们是怎么做的 他们做了些什么 他们是这样做的
What was found was that
人们发现
there are some distinguishing characteristics- two of them:
他们有一些特别的特质 有两点
they set rituals for themselves
他们为自己建立例行公事
and we talked about rituals in the past;
我们之前讲过例行公事的
the second thing that they do-
第二件事
and this is what I'm going to elaborate on now-
也就是我现在要详细讲的
the second thing that they do,in addition to having rituals,
他们所做的第二件事 除了建立例行公事
whether it's a lot of rituals,
不管是很多的例行公事
or few rituals,depending on individual needs and differences.
还是寥寥几件 视乎个人需要和个人差异
In addition to setting rituals,
除了建立例行公事
they particularly set rituals for both work and for recovery.
他们还特别地不仅为工作 还为恢复也建立了例行公事
Let me explain.Let me explain.
让我来解释一下 解释一下
What I'm going to say now
我现在要说的是
is some thing that psychologists did not see before,
心理学家以前没有意识到的
because it was hidden just like the children on the bus
因为它就像公车上的孩子一样隐藏着
or hidden by the first question.
或者被第一个问题掩盖着
It was only after asking the second question
只有问了第二个问题
that they notice this.
他们才会注意到
What they noticed was that these individuals ritualize work
他们注意到这些人将工作和恢复
and recovery and in essence what they found-
例行公事化 本质上他们发现的是
this is the most surprising result in my mind in studying stress-
这是我觉得研究压力时所得的最惊人的结果
is that stress was actually not the problem.
那就是问题其实不在于压力
We were looking in the wrong place.
我们找错了地方
In fact,what they found was stress was good for us!
事实上他们发现压力对我们是有好处的
That stress actually cultivated resilience,
压力实际上培养了我们的忍耐性
strength and helped us be happier in the long run.
力量 并且从长远来讲让我们更快乐
Wait a minute.
稍等片刻
What does that mean? Well,think about the following analogy.
这是什么意思呢 想想下面这个类比
Think about the physical realm.
想想运动方面
What happens to you,
你发生了什么
what actually happens to you when you go to the gym?
你去健身房时实际上发生了什么呢
when you go to the gym,you lift weights.
当你去健身房 你举重时
What are you doing to your muscle? You are stressing your muscle!
你对你的肌肉做了什么 你在给你的肌肉压力!
In fact,
事实上
you are carrying part of the- there are micro tears in your cells.
你其实就在... 你的细胞在偷偷流泪
Now is this a bad thing? That you are doing that?
请问这是坏事吗 你所做的事是坏事吗
Not at all! It's a good thing.
完全不是 这是件好事
Because you lift weights and then two days later,
因为你举重 然后两天之后
you lift these weights again.
再去举重
And the next week,you continue lifting these weights.
然后下周 你接着举重
And on and on.
长此以往
You do it for a month and two and four months and six months.
你举了一个月 两个月 四个 六个月
And after a year of lifting weights,you begin to look like me!
然后举了一年的重之后 你就会像我一样
Or maybe not.So the stress part is actually good for us.
或者也不会 所以压力其实对我们是有好处的
What's the problem though?
那真正的问题是什么呢
When do the problems begin with stressing those muscles?
比如说压缩肌肉时 问题是从什么时候开始的呢
It's when you lift weights,and a minute later,
是你去举重 然后一分钟之后
you lift the same weights again,
你又去举重
and again,and again,and again,and so on and so on.
然后不断举 不断举 不断不断地举
What would happen to you then,
然后会发生的事就是
if you don't take a break,whether it's a break between sessions,
如果你不休息 不管是运动之间的休息
whether it's break,days break? What happens to you then?
或者是休息几天 那么会发生什么呢
That's when you get injured.That's when you get hurt.
你就会受伤 到时你就会受伤
That's when you actually tear or pull a muscle.
那时你的肌肉就会拉伤
That's when you become over-worked-
那时你就会锻炼过度
and that has psychological as well as physical effects.
这既有生理上 也有心理上的影响
That's when you are over-trained.
这时候你就是锻炼过度了
In other words,the problem is not stress,
换言之 问题不在于压力
not on the physical level,nor on the psychological level.
不是生理上的问题 也不是心理上的问题
The problem is lack of recovery.
问题在于缺少恢复
Individuals who are both successful,happy,thriving,
那些既成功又快乐幸福的人
flourishing are ones who do experience stress.
是会感受到压力的
However,they also pay very close attention to recovery.
然而他们很注重恢复
Just like any athlete here in this room knows that
就好像在座的任何运动员都知道
you have tapering,you have time-off before important games.
你们会有调整期 在重要比赛前都会有休息
You don't lift the same weights day in and day out.
你们不会每天去举重
The same thing on the psychological level.
从心理层面上讲也是这样
If we don't take breaks,
如果我们不懂得休息
we will pay a price- on the physical level,we get injured;
我们会付出代价 在生理层面上 我们会受伤
on the psychological level,
在心理层面上
we experience anxiety,ultimately,potentially depression.
我们会感觉到焦虑 最终可能导致抑郁
Stress is fine.It's good.
压力没有关系 它是好事
It's exciting at times,if we also have recovery.
如果我们能恢复 它有时甚至是很令人兴奋的
I want to share with you now some more ideas
我想和你们再分享一些
from the book that I talked about before,
我之前提过的书里写的东西
"The Power of Full Engagement"-
《精力管理》
that again,I highly recommend you read.
我非常推荐你们读这本书
Maybe over your spring break.
也许在春假时你们可以读一读
And what Tony Schwartz and Jim Loehr talk about,
Tony Schwartz和Jim Loehr想说的是
is that what we need to do is change our perception of our day
我们所要做的是将我们对生活的理解
from being marathon runners to being sprinters,
从马拉松运动员变为短跑运动员
from going on and on and on
从不停地跑 跑 跑
to sprinting,recovery,sprinting,recovery.
变为短跑 恢复 短跑 恢复
That understanding,that understanding changed my life.
这个想法 这个想法改变了我的人生
I was a marathon runner,metaphorically- meaning at work.
我曾经是个马拉松运动员 我是指在工作上
I used to work 14 hours a day.
我每天工作14个小时
I loved my work.I worked extremely hard.
我热爱我的工作 非常努力
And then I decided to get married and to have children.
然后我决定结婚生子
And I knew that things would change as a result of that.
我知道因此可能一切会变得不一样
And I said,"OK.I have to compromise.
我说"好吧 我必须妥协
I have to work less than 14 hours a day,
我只能一天工作少于14个小时
if I want to maintain a healthy relationship
如果我想和我的妻子以及孩子
with my spouse and with my kids."
保持良好的关系的话"
And it disappointed me to some extent,but I have my priorities.
我某种程度上有点失望 但我有我优先的考虑
And I made a choice.
我做了这样的决定
And then I met Tony Schwartz,
然后我遇到了Tony Schwartz
who within a few minutes changed my perception,
他只用了几分钟就改变了我的观念
my understanding of what my day can and ought to look like.
改变了我对我的人生应该是怎么样的理解
And when he explained to me this,it made immediate sense.
当他跟我说时 我立即意识到就应该是这样的
I started to implement it.
我开始应用它
And today I may not be as productive as I was
而今天我可能没有一天工作14小时
when I worked for 14 hours a day,but very close to it.
那么有效率 但也十分接近了
And I'm certainly happier.
而我显然更快乐了
And I'm more creative than I was when I was a marathoner.
我比还是个"马拉松运动员"时更有创造力
And here is his suggestion-
他的建议是这样的
one of the things that he talks about in the book;
他书里讲到这样一个东西
this is a ritual that I recommend and it is:
这是我推荐的一种习惯
have 60 to 120 minutes,so around 90 minutes
用一到两个小时 也就是大约一个半小时
of sprint,work,concentrate,focus hard,go for it.
来"短跑" 专注地工作 精力非常集中
And then after that,after you sprint,
然后在那之后 "短跑"之后
with as little distraction as possible,
在尽可能少分心的情况下
have 15 minutes or so of recovery.
用十五分钟来恢复
What psychologist found is essentially we are able to sprint,
心理学家发现我们能够"短跑"
to focus,according to our bio-rhythms,
能够专注 按照我们的生物钟
between 60 and 120 minutes- it differs.
能持续一到两个小时 每个人可能不同
Some people are more 60; others can do it for two hours.
有些人是一个小时 有些人可以持续两小时
Average: 90 minutes.After you sprint,take 15 minutes off,
平均是一个半小时 "短跑"之后 休息十五分钟
whether it's for meditation,
可以是冥想
listening to your favorite piece of music;
听你最喜欢的音乐
whether it's for going to the gym-
也可以是去健身
can be of course more than 15 minutes,but at least 15 minutes;
可以多于十五分钟 但至少要十五分钟
having lunch,having a break- and during lunch,
吃午饭 休息一下 但在午饭时
not doing emails and being on the phone,
不收邮件 不接电话
which only adds to the stress-
那些只会增加焦虑
really relaxing with friends or by ourselves.
而是和朋友一起或独自完全放松
And when we have a day that
如果我们的一天是
structured with sprint,recovery,sprint,recovery,
短跑 恢复 短跑 恢复
that's when we can sustain,
我们就能持续
when we have a higher levels of energy,
能够维持高水平的精力
when we get the most done and when we are happiest.
做更多的工作 并且更快乐
This is my day now.
我现在的生活就是如此
My day comprises sprint,recovery,sprint,recovery.
我的一天就是短跑 恢复 短跑 恢复
I'm able to get so much more done.
我能做更多的工作
My ideal day,work day is 90 minutes,15 minutes meditation;
我理想的一天就是一个半小时工作 十五分钟冥想
90 minutes,lunch; 90 minutes,work out;
一个半小时 午餐 一个半小时 运动
90 minutes,home with family.
一个半小时 回家和家人在一起
Actually net- I work for 6 hours a day.
我一天净工作6个小时
But in those 6 hours,
但在这6个小时中
I get more than I would have in 10- not to mention the fact
我能做比十小时还多的事 更不用说
that I am happier and more creative doing it.
我更快乐 并且更有创造性了
The key when doing it is to maintain flexibility,
这样的关键在于维持灵活性
because- again,the ideal day for me would be that.
因为... 对我来说理想的一天是这样的
However,there are other things,
然而总是有一些别的事
you know- I travel a lot; I teach a class.
比如我经常出差 我要教课
During those times,let's say I'm not by my computer,
在这种时候 我不在电脑旁
writing or doing research- again,
写东西或做研究
because these are important things to me.
但是因为这些事对我来说很重要
So what would I have done for example
所以我会做的是 比如说
is say I want ten 90 minutes sessions,
我要十个一个半小时的时间段
the ritual of ten 90 minutes session a week.
例行的每周十个一个半小时时间段
Some of these 90 minutes sessions are on a flight and that's OK.
有一些这种时间段是在飞机上 这没关系
Some of these 90 minutes sessions are at home or in my office.
有一些时间段我在家里或者在办公室里
But at least ten,usually more than ten,
但每周至少要有十个 通常多于十个
90 minutes sessions a week.And when I have it,I'm happy.
一个半小时的时间段 当我做到时 我很快乐
I feel good.I get a lot done.Also,the ritual of yoga.
我感觉很好 我做了很多事 又比如瑜伽的习惯
Maintain flexibility there.
维持灵活性
So one of the things that are difficult for me
对我来说很困难的一件事就是
is to introduce a 45 minutes or one hour session a day.
每天留出45分钟或一个小时的时间段
And yoga is important for me.
但瑜伽对我来说很重要
It makes me feel good.
它使我感觉良好
And I'll talk about the research around it after break.
我在放假回来之后会谈到关于它的研究
So what I started to do was breaking down yoga sessions and
所以我所做的是 拆分瑜伽的时间段
now part of my 15 minutes in between is 15 minute yoga,sunset
现在那15分钟的间隔有时是15分钟的瑜伽
For 15 minutes
15分钟的日落瑜伽
and then the next 15 minutes is another part of yoga practice.
然后下一个15分钟做另一种瑜伽练习
So I break yoga into two or three sessions a day instead of one.
所以我将瑜伽拆分成每天两到三个时间段
Again,the flexibility of ritual.
又是例行公事的灵活性
And that for me works.Works very well.
这对我来说有用 非常有效
The key is,and I am going to end with this-
关键在于 我最后要讲讲这个
the key is to attain multi-level recovery.
关键在于保证不同程度的恢复
First recovery: on the micro level.
第一种恢复 从最小的级别
15 minutes meditation,one hour of gym,
15分钟的冥想 一小时健身
whatever it is,a lunch break.
或者是午餐休息 随便什么
Middle: mezo level recovery and that is a good night sleep.
中间级别的恢复就是睡一个好觉
We'll talk about the importance of sleep-
我们会讲到睡觉的重要性
sleep is a good investment for well being,
睡眠是对幸福 对快乐 对创造力
happiness as well as for you creativity,for your memory.
以及对你的记忆力的重要投资
Sleep is important.A day off during the week.
睡眠很重要 每周都要休息一天
Even God needed a day off.Implemented in our lives.
即使上帝也需要一天的休息 我们的生活也是这样
And finally,those vacations.Remember J.P.Morgan:
最后就是假期 J.P.Morgan说过
"I can do the work of a year in 9 months,
"我可以一年工作九个月
but not in 12." Recreation leads to creation.
但不能工作12个月" 娱乐带来创造力
So remember that.Remember that.
记住这一点 请记住这一点
Next week,we meet on Tuesday here for the midterm.
下周二我们会在这里进行期中考试
Thursday- we don't have class.And remember the vacation.
周四不用上课 记住假期就应该
Take time.Enjoy it.And good luck.See you after break.
好好地享受 祝你们好运 假期后见